acnestudios.com 2019-05-06

# Acne Studios - Privacy policy

#### 1\. Introduction

Acne Studios recognizes the importance of protecting the privacy of your personal data. We have instituted strict policies and security measures to protect the information you provide us. The words “personal data” where used in this Privacy Policy has the same meaning as “personal information”, as defined in accordance with Section 6 of the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth). 

#### 2\. Who is responsible for the processing of your personal data?

The Swedish company Acne Studios AB, reg. No. 556504-7726 (“Acne Studios”), is the controller of your personal data. Acne Studios’ affiliated companies (including other companies within the Acne Studios group, joint ventures, franchisees and licensees) and selected suppliers may process your personal data on Acne Studios’ behalf and in accordance with Acne Studios’ instructions as stated below and are thereby processors of your personal data. You may contact Acne Studios at any time, please find our contact details below.   
Mail address: P.O. Box 24266, 104 51 Stockholm, Sweden   
Visiting address: Floragatan 13, 114 31 Stockholm, Sweden   
Phone: [+46 10 888 73 05](tel:+46108887305)   
E-mail: [customercare@acnestudios.com](mailto:customercare@acnestudios.com)   
You may contact our Data Protection Officer at [DPO@acnestudios.com](mailto:DPO@acnestudios.com)

#### 3\. Categories of data processed, purpose and legal basis for processing

##### 3.1 General

Below is a summary of the categories of data that we process, the purposes of processing the data and on what legal basis we are processing your data. Our processing of your personal data partly depends on whether you have subscribed for membership with us or not. The processing of personal data relating to customers that are not members is described in section 3.2 below. The processing of our members’ personal data is described in section 3.3 below. 

##### 3.2 Customers (non-members)

##### 3.2.1 Data collected when you shop in our webstore or use our online services

_Contact details:_ If you make a purchase online we will collect your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, country of residence, date of birth, title (Ms./Mr. or other title) and social media account contact details. Not all information is mandatory for making a purchase. We have marked mandatory information with the symbol (*) on our website. We will use your contact information to (i) process your purchase/orders and any returns, exchanges and complaints you may have relating to your purchase; and to (ii) communicate with you regarding your purchase and to answer and administer any questions or comments you may have regarding our products or services. The legal basis is that it is necessary to process your data in order for us to be able to fulfill our contractual obligations to you under the purchase agreement. We will retain your data for as long as necessary for this purpose. We may also process your contact details to keep you informed, via email, SMS, letters, telephone, WeChat, Whatsapp and other social media, of our special events or promotions. The legal basis is our legitimate interest of being able to market our products to our existing customers. We may use your contact details for direct marketing purposes for up to 12 months after your latest purchase subject to your ongoing right to opt-out. You are entitled to reject our marketing messages at any time by clicking on the unsubscribe link included in each message or by contacting customer service at [customercare@acnestudios.com](mailto:customercare@acnestudios.com). 

_Credit card details:_ If you make a purchase online and chose to pay by credit card, you will provide your credit card information on our website to finalize your purchase. Your credit card details will be protected using Global Sign Encryption. The legal basis is that the processing is necessary in order for us to be able to fulfill our contractual obligations to you under the purchase agreement. We will retain your data for as long as necessary for this purpose.

_Previous purchases and returns:_ If you have signed up for an account we will store information regarding (i) your purchases and returns online, and (ii) your purchases and returns in physical stores, if you have provided your e-mail address to our personnel. Such information encompasses product, size, price and date of purchase. We will also store information regarding your recently viewed items. This will allow you to keep track of your purchases and returns, and recently viewed items, by logging into your personal account. The legal basis is our legitimate interest to provide you with the service of a personal account as requested by you when you signed up for the account. You may choose to deregister your account at any time. We will also save information on your contact details and previous purchases and returns during 36 months after the purchase to be able to administer returns and/or complaints. The legal basis is our legitimate interest to provide our customers with speedy and efficient service after the purchase. 

##### 3.2.2 Data collected when you shop in our physical stores

If you make a purchase in one of our physical stores we may process your e-mail address in order to be able to send a digital receipt to you. We will only collect your email address and send you a digital receipt if this has been requested or accepted by you. This processing is based on our legitimate interest of being able to provide our customers with a digital receipt on a voluntary basis. We will retain your data for as long as necessary for this purpose. 

##### 3.3 Members

You may sign up for membership by subscribing to the services provided by Acne Studios in accordance with the Membership Policy. The membership is completely voluntary and subscribing for membership is not a requirement for purchasing Acne Studios’ goods. When you subscribe to become a member, you will enter into an agreement with Acne Studios (the Membership Policy). 

##### 3.3.1 Data collected when signing up for membership

When you sign up for membership (online or in Acne Studios’ physical stores), Acne Studios collects your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, country of residence, date of birth, title (Ms./Mr. or other title) and social media account contact details. Acne Studios processes the data to create your personal account and to process the membership which includes certain features such as (i) sending digital receipts upon request when purchasing a product in a physical store, (ii) sending out invitations to special events/promotions, (iii) personalized services in store, and (iv) profiled marketing offers through email, SMS, letters, telephone, WeChat, Whatsapp and other social media. The legal basis is that the processing is necessary in order for us to be able to fulfill our contractual obligations to you under the Membership Policy. We will retain your data for as long as necessary for this purpose. 

##### 3.3.2 Data collected when shopping online

_Contact details:_ When you purchase a product online, Acne Studios will process your contact details for the following purposes; (i) to process purchases/orders and returns, exchanges and complaints; (ii) to communicate with you regarding the purchases and to answer and administer any questions or comments that you may have regarding Acne Studios’ products or services. The legal basis is that the processing is necessary in order for us to be able to fulfill our contractual obligations to you under the purchase agreement. 

_Previous purchases and returns:_ Acne Studios will also process data regarding your contact details and previous purchases and returns online (product, size, price and date of purchase) during 36 months after the purchase. The information will be processed for the following purposes:   
Administering returns and complaints. The processing is based on our legitimate interest to provide our members with speedy and efficient service after the purchase.   
Allowing you to keep track of your purchases and returns by logging into your account. The legal basis is that the processing is necessary in order for us to be able to fulfill our contractual obligations to you under the Membership Policy.   
For the purpose of sending out invitations to special events/promotions, personalized services in store and profiled marketing offers through email, SMS, letters, telephone, WeChat, Whatsapp and other social media. The legal basis is that the processing is necessary in order for us to be able to fulfill our contractual obligations to you under the Membership Policy. 

_Credit card details:_ If you make a purchase online and chose to pay by credit card, you will provide your credit card information on the website for the purpose of making payment for the purchase. The legal basis is that the processing is necessary in order for us to be able to fulfill our contractual obligations to you under the purchase agreement. As a member you may also choose to save your credit card details for future purchases, for the purpose of speeding up the checkout the next time you shop. The legal basis for this processing is your consent. We will retain your data for as long as necessary for this purpose. 

##### 3.3.3 Data collected when shopping in physical stores

When you shop in Acne Studios’ physical stores, Acne Studios may collect and store information regarding (i) your clothing and shoe size, (ii) your clothing preferences (such as preferred colors and style) and (iii) other shopping preferences, provided that you have shared this information with Acne Studios’ personnel on a voluntary basis. Acne Studios may also store data regarding your purchases and returns in physical stores (product, size, price and date of purchase) if you have provided your e-mail address to Acne Studios’ personnel. This information is processed for the purpose of enhancing your future purchasing experience with Acne Studios and to provide customized service, which is part of Acne Studios’ membership service. Acne Studios may also use the information regarding your shopping preferences for the purpose of sending out invitations to special events/promotions and profiled marketing offers through email, SMS, letters, telephone, WeChat, Whatsapp and other social media. The legal basis for this is that the processing is necessary in order for us to be able to fulfill our contractual obligations to you under the Membership Policy. We will retain your data for as long as necessary for this purpose. 

##### 3.3.4 Data collected when using Acne Studios website services

Acne Studios will store information regarding your recently viewed items when browsing Acne Studios’ website. This will allow you to keep track of your recently viewed items, by logging into your personal account. The legal basis for this is that the processing is necessary in order for us to be able to fulfill our contractual obligations to you under the Membership Policy. We will retain your data for as long as necessary for this purpose. 

##### 3.4 Newsletter Subscribers

If you have subscribed to one of our newsletters, we will use your contact details to send out such newsletter. The legal basis for this processing is your consent. The newsletters will be sent to you until you unsubscribe to the newsletter service. 

##### 3.5 Archive Subscribers

If you have subscribed to receive information and updates via e-mail and text messages regarding Acne Studios Archive events, we will process your name, telephone number, e-mail address, country of residence and gender to send out information regarding Archive events. The legal basis for this processing is your consent. The information and updates regarding Archive events will be sent to you until you unsubscribe to the service. 

##### 3.6 Customer service

If you have contacted Acne Studios regarding a complaint, return or question, the e-mail or chat conversation will be stored for as long as it is necessary to administer your matter, including following up on the matter within 12 months. Depending on the nature of the matter for which you are contacting us, the legal basis may be that our processing is necessary for us to be able to fulfill our obligations under the purchase agreement or Membership Policy, or that we have a legitimate interest of being able to communicate with individuals who contact our customer service 

##### 3.7 Anonymized data

It can be noted that we may also use _anonymized data_ for our internal marketing and demographic studies to analyze, profile and monitor customer patterns in order for us to be able to improve our products and services. 

##### 3.8 Consent and withdrawal

You hereby confirm that you have read and understood the content of this privacy policy. Where the legal basis for the processing of your personal data is your consent you agree to Acne Studios’ processing of your personal data in accordance with the provisions herein. Should you wish to object to, or withdraw your consent, to any of our processing, please contact us at [customercare@acnestudios.com](mailto:customercare@acnestudios.com). Please note, however, that your withdrawal will not affect our right to process your data when such processing is necessary to perform our contractual obligations to you, and/or to the extent we are required to process your data by law or to defend ourselves in a dispute, to prevent fraud or abuse, or to enforce our Terms and Conditions. If you withdraw your consent to any consent-based processing, we will cease all such processing. 

#### 4\. Does Acne Studios share your information with others?

Acne Studios does not sell or rent our customer’s personal data to any other entity.   
We may share your data with affiliated companies including other companies within the Acne Studios group, joint ventures, franchisees and licensees. If you have subscribed for membership with Acne Studios, we may combine your data provided to us with data that you have provided to such affiliated companies, for the purpose of improving our services to you, and to enhance your shopping experience when visiting an Acne Studios store in another country than your residence. The legal basis for the processing is that it is necessary for Acne Studios’ performance of the Membership Policy.   
Acne Studios may also share your data with selected suppliers who perform functions on our behalf such as fulfilling orders and delivery of orders, processing payments, carrying out promotional services or data management, to maintain our website, to distribute e-mails, to send out our newsletter, to provide client communications and to manage our customer database. As necessary, the personal data you provide to us may be processed by these third parties, solely on Acne Studios’ behalf and in accordance with Acne Studios’ instructions as data processors. We do not authorize any of our suppliers to make any other use of your personal data.   
If Acne Studios and/or its subsidiaries are subject to an actual or potential merger or acquisition or similar transaction, we may share your data with potential and actual buyer(s) and their financial and legal advisers, subject to such third parties undertaking appropriate confidentiality.   

#### 5\. Transfer outside of Australia and EU/EES

We may share your data with our selected suppliers, who may process your data in countries both inside and outside of Australia and the EU/EEA when performing functions on our behalf as set out in section 4 above.   
If you have subscribed to membership with Acne Studios, we will share your contact details and information on previous purchases and shopping preferences with our affiliated companies both inside and outside of Australia and the EU/EEA (please see further under section 4).   
Please note that countries outside of Australia and the EU/EEA may not provide an adequate level of protection for your personal data. Acne Studios has however taken appropriate safeguards to ensure that the receiving parties of your data in countries outside of Australia or the EU/EEA shall provide an adequate protection of your data. Such safeguards may be that the receiving party has joined the Privacy Shield (if the receiving party is a company established in the United States) or that the receiving party has signed so called standard data protection clauses adopted by the EU Commission. Please contact us at [customercare@acnestudios.com](mailto:customercare@acnestudios.com) if you want further information on what safeguards have been taken and if you want a copy of such safeguards. 

#### 6\. Your data subject rights

In this section 6, we have summarized your data subject rights to request access, portability, rectification, erasure of your personal data, to restrict the processing of your personal data, to object to processing, and your right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority.   
If you want to exercise your rights, please send us an email at [customercare@acnestudios.com](mailto:customercare@acnestudios.com). Please note however that if you want to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority, you need to contact the authority directly.   
If you have signed up for a membership with Acne Studios you will also be able to access, rectify and erase some of your data by logging in to your private account. [Login to your account](https://www.acnestudios.com/my-account)   
Notwithstanding anything to the contrary herein, Acne Studios reserves the right to keep and process your personal data in accordance with this policy to the extent necessary to perform our contractual obligations to you, and to the extent we are required to process your data by law or in order to defend ourselves in a dispute, to prevent fraud or abuse, or to enforce our Terms and Conditions.

_Right of access_   
You have the right to obtain confirmation of whether personal data concerning yourself are being processed and, where that is the case, access to the personal data and information regarding, inter alia, the purpose of processing, the categories of personal data concerned, the categories of recipients to whom your data have been or will be disclosed, and the envisaged period of time for which personal data will be stored (or the criteria for determining this). 

_Right of rectification_   
You have the right to request rectification of inaccurate personal data concerning yourself, and to complete incomplete data.   

_Right of erasure_   
Under certain circumstances you are entitled to request that we erase your personal data or restrict our processing of your data, namely in the following events.   
When it is no longer necessary for us to process your data taking into consideration the purposes for which it was collected.   
When our processing is based on your consent and you have withdrawn your consent, and there is no other legal basis for the processing of your data.   
When our processing of your data is based on a legitimate interest legal basis and you object to such processing, and there is no overriding legitimate ground for our processing.   
When you have objected to our processing of your data for direct marketing purposes.   
When your personal data has been unlawfully processed.   
When the personal data must be erased for compliance with a legal obligation that applies to us.   
When the personal data collected concerns a child (under 13 years of age) in relation to the offer of information society services. 

_Right to objection - direct marketing and profiling_   
You have the right to object at any time to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes, which includes profiling to the extent that it is related to such direct marketing. If you object to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes, including profiling, we will cease such processing of your data. 

_Data portability_   
If our processing is based on your consent or if the processing is necessary for our performance of a contract with you, you have the right to request that the data which you have provided to us shall be provided to you in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and you also have the right to transmit such data to another controller. 

_Right to lodge a complaint with supervisory authority_   
Please note that if you consider the processing of your data to be in violation of applicable data protection laws, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Office of The Australian Information Commissioner at https://www.oaic.gov.au and the Swedish Data Inspection Board. 

#### 7\. How do I unsubscribe from Acne Studios newsletters and emails?

If you do no longer wish to receive our newsletters or other emails, you can unsubscribe as indicated in the particular communication, i.e. by using the unsubscribe link which is included on all newsletters and other emails. You may also contact us at [customercare@acnestudios.com](mailto:customercare@acnestudios.com).

#### 8\. How long do we keep your data?

We will retain your personal information for as long as necessary in relation to the purposes for which the data was collected or otherwise processed. Under section 3 above, we have specified the retention time, or the criteria for determining the retention time, for our processing of data in relation to the different purposes the data is being processed. In addition to the retention time stated under section 3 above, please also note the following.   
Members: If you have not made any purchases, logged in to your account or used any of our services during a consecutive period of 36 months, we will terminate your membership and consequently we will not use your data for any membership services or marketing purposes thereafter. In such case we will delete your data unless we need to keep it for other purposes that are legally justifiable.   
We will retain your personal information as necessary to comply with applicable legal obligations, to resolve disputes, and to enforce our agreements. Statutory obligations to retain data further remain unaffected. 

#### 9\. Is it mandatory to provide personal data?

When you purchase our products online, or sign up for a membership with Acne Studios, we will inform you which data is mandatory by marking certain fields with a symbol (*). The provision of mandatory data is necessary for Acne Studios to be able to fulfill our contractual obligation to you, for example processing your order, or fulfilling the membership services requested by you.   
When you purchase our products in our physical stores, you do not have to provide any personal data. Please note however that if you chose to receive a digital receipt, it is mandatory that you provide your e-mail address or otherwise we will not be able to send you the digital receipt. 

#### 10\. Children's privacy and legal purchase age

Acne Studios does not wish to collect personal information from anyone under the age of (18). If you are under eighteen (18), we require that you inform and get your parents’ or guardians’ consent before purchasing anything or provide any personal data to us at acnestudios.com or any other website related to Acne Studios.

#### 11\. Cookies

We use cookies on our website. Please see our separate policy for cookies, which you can find on our website.

#### 12\. Modifications

Acne Studios reserves the right to occasionally make changes to our privacy policy or practices. We will post the updated policy on our website, and thus we encourage you to review this page from time to time.   
Last date for modification: May, 2018
